

Damyana Stoyanova

I explore solutions with design and code, based on data. Currently working on an end-to-end market research internal platform in

MetrixLab B.V. I like UX because of its impact, making people's lives better while helping businesses grow and decrease risk. That's why I enjoy advocating for the benefits of user-centered design. I love interesting challenges and learning from colleagues, as well as sharing my own experience, encouraging each other to explore, test and craft the best solutions.

© Rotterdam, Netherlands LinkedIn profile hello@damyana.design +31 6 45 59 63 61

WORK EXPERIENCE

JAN 2023 - PRESENT, ROTTERDAM

UX/UI DESIGNER | MetrixLab B.V.

- collaborated with cross-functional scrum teams on end-to-end platform for research.
- did competitor research to identify business opportunities and assist product owners and other team members.
- helped maintain and worked with design system.
- helped agile teams decrease business risk by exploring and testing various solutions - using various methods from research and user tests to sketches, wireframes, Figma or Angular prototypes.
- explored complex user, information flows and service interactions to help build an end-to-end research process platform.
- built interactive prototypes using HTML/CSS/JS or Angular to test with users and improve dev handoff.

DEC 2019 - JAN 2023, REMOTE

UX/UI DESIGNER | BILDA Rainscreen

- bounce rates decreased from 88% to 58% with a website redesign.
- collaborate with client's team, deliver sketches, wireframes and Figma prototype, develop in WordPress. All based on UX research and data about target audience.
- create a style guide and a collection of visual assets.
- continuously monitor analytics, session recordings to improve chosen metrics.
- create landing pages and continuously design and develop interactive UI elements to showcase BILDA's unique value proposition.

DEC 2019 - PRESENT, ROTTERDAM

UX/UI DESIGNER | damyana.design

- collaborated with teams, keeping track of metrics towards chosen goals.
- UX audits competitor research, stakeholder interviews, heuristic analysis of desktop or mobile web flows, monitoring analytics and session recordings to find pain points and improve conversions.
- summarized research insights, offered and tested potential solutions.
- created personas and user journeys based on research data.
- created print and digital materials to solve pain points in customer journey and achieve business goals.
- collaborated with international and local organisations and companies: WWF Netherlands, AIP Foundation, Inclusive Action for the City, Climable, WiNGS, bilda.net, bilda.nz, meedeethaikitchen.com, dkayhomegoods.com.
- \$32k total impact assisting NGOs on catchafire.org

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF EDINBURGH Digital Media Design MSc.

2019 - 2022

Specialized in UX, UI and coding prototypes. The thesis focused on creating and iterating on a browser extension to help people with ADHD have a calmer browsing experience. In my research, I explored topics like PIM, gamification, applying behavioural science principles for behavioural change.

SKILLS & TOOLS

UX research, UX design, visual design, UI design, user interviews, user testing, sketching, wireframing, interactive coded prototypes, maintaining design systems

Figma, HTML/CSS/JS, Angular, Bootstrap, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Jira, Miro

CERTIFICATIONS

How to design for accessibility (WCAG 2.0) Professional Scrum with UXI - Scrum.org Clean code - Udemy UX Research for Agile Teams - LinkedIn Design Practice in Business - DelftX GDPR Compliance Essential Training Design Thinking Practitioner - IBM Discovery Program - Accenture Enterprise Foundation - Edinburgh Innovations

LANGUAGES

English - C2 (IELTS 8.5) Dutch - C1

HOBBIES

In my free time I hike, read fantasy books, play PC games or play bass with my band.